<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>

<rdf:RDF
 xmlns:rdf="http://www.w3.org/1999/02/22-rdf-syntax-ns#"
 xmlns="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/"
 xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/"
 xmlns:taxo="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/taxonomy/"
 xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/"
 xmlns:syn="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/syndication/"
 xmlns:prism="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/prism/"
 xmlns:admin="http://webns.net/mvcb/"
>

<channel rdf:about="http://sih.sagepub.com">
<title>Studies in History recent issues</title>
<link>http://sih.sagepub.com</link>
<description>Studies in History RSS feed -- recent issues</description>
<prism:eIssn>0973-080X</prism:eIssn>
<prism:publicationName>Studies in History</prism:publicationName>
<prism:issn>0257-6430</prism:issn>
<items>
 <rdf:Seq>
  <rdf:li rdf:resource="http://sih.sagepub.com/cgi/reprint/27/2/149?rss=1" />
  <rdf:li rdf:resource="http://sih.sagepub.com/cgi/content/abstract/27/2/155?rss=1" />
  <rdf:li rdf:resource="http://sih.sagepub.com/cgi/content/abstract/27/2/197?rss=1" />
  <rdf:li rdf:resource="http://sih.sagepub.com/cgi/content/abstract/27/2/221?rss=1" />
  <rdf:li rdf:resource="http://sih.sagepub.com/cgi/content/abstract/27/2/251?rss=1" />
  <rdf:li rdf:resource="http://sih.sagepub.com/cgi/content/abstract/27/2/269?rss=1" />
  <rdf:li rdf:resource="http://sih.sagepub.com/cgi/content/abstract/27/2/281?rss=1" />
  <rdf:li rdf:resource="http://sih.sagepub.com/cgi/content/abstract/27/1/1?rss=1" />
  <rdf:li rdf:resource="http://sih.sagepub.com/cgi/content/abstract/27/1/21?rss=1" />
  <rdf:li rdf:resource="http://sih.sagepub.com/cgi/content/abstract/27/1/41?rss=1" />
  <rdf:li rdf:resource="http://sih.sagepub.com/cgi/content/abstract/27/1/55?rss=1" />
  <rdf:li rdf:resource="http://sih.sagepub.com/cgi/content/abstract/27/1/85?rss=1" />
  <rdf:li rdf:resource="http://sih.sagepub.com/cgi/content/abstract/27/1/111?rss=1" />
  <rdf:li rdf:resource="http://sih.sagepub.com/cgi/reprint/27/1/131?rss=1" />
  <rdf:li rdf:resource="http://sih.sagepub.com/cgi/reprint/27/1/133?rss=1" />
  <rdf:li rdf:resource="http://sih.sagepub.com/cgi/reprint/27/1/136?rss=1" />
  <rdf:li rdf:resource="http://sih.sagepub.com/cgi/reprint/27/1/141?rss=1" />
  <rdf:li rdf:resource="http://sih.sagepub.com/cgi/content/abstract/27/1/147?rss=1" />
  <rdf:li rdf:resource="http://sih.sagepub.com/cgi/content/abstract/26/2/103?rss=1" />
  <rdf:li rdf:resource="http://sih.sagepub.com/cgi/content/abstract/26/2/143?rss=1" />
  <rdf:li rdf:resource="http://sih.sagepub.com/cgi/content/abstract/26/2/175?rss=1" />
  <rdf:li rdf:resource="http://sih.sagepub.com/cgi/content/abstract/26/2/211?rss=1" />
  <rdf:li rdf:resource="http://sih.sagepub.com/cgi/content/abstract/26/2/227?rss=1" />
  <rdf:li rdf:resource="http://sih.sagepub.com/cgi/reprint/26/2/245?rss=1" />
  <rdf:li rdf:resource="http://sih.sagepub.com/cgi/reprint/26/2/250?rss=1" />
  <rdf:li rdf:resource="http://sih.sagepub.com/cgi/reprint/26/2/254?rss=1" />
  <rdf:li rdf:resource="http://sih.sagepub.com/cgi/content/abstract/26/1/1?rss=1" />
  <rdf:li rdf:resource="http://sih.sagepub.com/cgi/content/abstract/26/1/31?rss=1" />
  <rdf:li rdf:resource="http://sih.sagepub.com/cgi/content/abstract/26/1/61?rss=1" />
  <rdf:li rdf:resource="http://sih.sagepub.com/cgi/reprint/26/1/91?rss=1" />
  <rdf:li rdf:resource="http://sih.sagepub.com/cgi/reprint/26/1/96?rss=1" />
 </rdf:Seq>
</items>
<image rdf:resource="http://sih.sagepub.com:80/icons/banner/title.gif" />
</channel>
<image rdf:about="http://sih.sagepub.com:80/icons/banner/title.gif">
<title>Studies in History</title>
<url>http://sih.sagepub.com:80/icons/banner/title.gif</url>
<link>http://sih.sagepub.com</link>
</image>
<item rdf:about="http://sih.sagepub.com/cgi/reprint/27/2/149?rss=1">
<title><![CDATA[Introduction]]></title>
<link>http://sih.sagepub.com/cgi/reprint/27/2/149?rss=1</link>
<description><![CDATA[]]></description>
<dc:creator><![CDATA[Chojnacki, C., Haider, N.]]></dc:creator>
<dc:date>2013-01-23T10:08:20-08:00</dc:date>
<dc:identifier>info:doi/10.1177/0257643012459414</dc:identifier>
<dc:identifier>hwp:resource-id:spsih;27/2/149</dc:identifier>
<dc:title><![CDATA[Introduction]]></dc:title>
<prism:publicationDate>2011-08-01</prism:publicationDate>
<prism:section>Articles</prism:section>
<prism:volume>27</prism:volume>
<prism:number>2</prism:number>
<prism:startingPage>149</prism:startingPage>
<prism:endingPage>153</prism:endingPage>
<prism:issueName>Special Issue: The Dynamics of Religious Pluralism: Conflicts, Assimilation and Innovation in Pre-modern India</prism:issueName>
</item>
<item rdf:about="http://sih.sagepub.com/cgi/content/abstract/27/2/155?rss=1">
<title><![CDATA[Ambivalent Representations of Muslims in Medieval Indian Theatre]]></title>
<link>http://sih.sagepub.com/cgi/content/abstract/27/2/155?rss=1</link>
<description><![CDATA[
<p>From the eleventh century AD onwards, some Indian dramatists began to derive the plot of their plays from contemporary events, such as the military achievements of their patron, despite the prohibition of this kind of subjects by theoreticians. As the neighbouring Afghan and Turkish rulers of Ghazna and Ghur were threatening India then, Muslim characters made their appearance in some of these historical plays, like Somadeva&rsquo;s <I>Lalitavigraharaja</I> (<I>c</I>. AD 1153) and Jayasimhasuri&rsquo;s <I>Hammiramadamardana</I> (<I>c</I>. AD 1227&ndash;30). Consequently, these texts constitute a counterpoint to the Persian chronicles and give us the unique opportunity of ascertaining how Muslim invaders were perceived by Indian people during the political upheavals of the twelfth and thirteenth centuries ad. The article first analyzes how Muslim characters are reviled and even demonized by means of specific dramatic languages as well as other literary devices, and then demonstrates that Muslim people were far from being the only target of this process of demonization: according to the circumstances, it was also used by devotees of Visnu against Jains, Jains against followers of Siva and even between rival sects of one and a same religion. Furthermore the plays betray a genuine acquaintance of their authors with the realities of the Islamic world. Though portraying Muslim characters in a more virulent way than Somadeva, Jayasimhasuri transposed foreign names into Sanskrit rather carefully and gave a faithful account of the political, military and cultural particularities of Muslim people.</p>
]]></description>
<dc:creator><![CDATA[Leclere, B.]]></dc:creator>
<dc:date>2013-01-23T10:08:20-08:00</dc:date>
<dc:identifier>info:doi/10.1177/0257643012459415</dc:identifier>
<dc:identifier>hwp:resource-id:spsih;27/2/155</dc:identifier>
<dc:title><![CDATA[Ambivalent Representations of Muslims in Medieval Indian Theatre]]></dc:title>
<prism:publicationDate>2011-08-01</prism:publicationDate>
<prism:section>Articles</prism:section>
<prism:volume>27</prism:volume>
<prism:number>2</prism:number>
<prism:startingPage>155</prism:startingPage>
<prism:endingPage>195</prism:endingPage>
<prism:issueName>Special Issue: The Dynamics of Religious Pluralism: Conflicts, Assimilation and Innovation in Pre-modern India</prism:issueName>
</item>
<item rdf:about="http://sih.sagepub.com/cgi/content/abstract/27/2/197?rss=1">
<title><![CDATA[Shifting Communities in Early Jain Prabandha Literature: Sectarian Attitudes and Emergent Identities]]></title>
<link>http://sih.sagepub.com/cgi/content/abstract/27/2/197?rss=1</link>
<description><![CDATA[
<p>Taking up the still debated question whether Muslims and particularly Hindus were or were not aware of forming a common religious community before the nineteenth century, David N. Lorenzen stated in the introduction to his essay <I>Who Invented Hinduism?</I> published in 2009 that the term Hinduism designed religious identity as early as the fifteenth century in Hindu texts and even one century earlier in inscriptions. However, most scholars did not take into account the Jain texts, probably because it was more or less unconsciously admitted that Jains are in fact Hindus. Nevertheless, the testimony of Jain Prabandhas, a new genre which includes biographies, eulogies and chronicles, reveals to be of peculiar interest. Indeed, on one hand, the Prabandhas attest that the Jains saw themselves as different to the Hindu sects and that they competed for instance with devotees of Siva in order to obtain the favour of a sovereign or to control a sacred place. On the other hand, the Jain authors do not go so far as to assimilate Muslims and Hindus into a single composite &lsquo;other&rsquo;. Rather they identify a double &lsquo;other&rsquo; represented by the non-Jains in the Indian world and by the Muslim newcomers. The terms in use are analyzed through various examples. Besides, as opposed to this double &lsquo;other&rsquo;, the Jains seem to have developed a sense of a larger community. As a matter of fact, if they go on using terms which apply to members of one and the same sectarian group, they also overcome sectarian divisions. Furthermore, by borrowing from Persian sources the term <I>hinduka</I>, they reveal that the advent of a foreign elite entailed the emergence of new identities.</p>
]]></description>
<dc:creator><![CDATA[Chojnacki, C.]]></dc:creator>
<dc:date>2013-01-23T10:08:20-08:00</dc:date>
<dc:identifier>info:doi/10.1177/0257643012459416</dc:identifier>
<dc:identifier>hwp:resource-id:spsih;27/2/197</dc:identifier>
<dc:title><![CDATA[Shifting Communities in Early Jain Prabandha Literature: Sectarian Attitudes and Emergent Identities]]></dc:title>
<prism:publicationDate>2011-08-01</prism:publicationDate>
<prism:section>Articles</prism:section>
<prism:volume>27</prism:volume>
<prism:number>2</prism:number>
<prism:startingPage>197</prism:startingPage>
<prism:endingPage>219</prism:endingPage>
<prism:issueName>Special Issue: The Dynamics of Religious Pluralism: Conflicts, Assimilation and Innovation in Pre-modern India</prism:issueName>
</item>
<item rdf:about="http://sih.sagepub.com/cgi/content/abstract/27/2/221?rss=1">
<title><![CDATA[The Throne of Worship: An 'Archaeological Tell' of Religious Rivalries]]></title>
<link>http://sih.sagepub.com/cgi/content/abstract/27/2/221?rss=1</link>
<description><![CDATA[
<p>The throne of worship, which is typically a colourful grotesque of theriomorphic theologemes that is to be visualized similarly in both internal and external worship, is a common feature of most surviving tantric literature. We may often read of ritual and doctrine being locked in so close an embrace that the one may not be interpreted without the other<sup>2</sup> and it is certainly true that their relationship can very often be demonstrated. Indeed, one article known to me demonstrates it with respect to the throne of worship: Sanderson<sup>3</sup> has pointed out that the enthronement of the three deities&mdash;Para, Parapara and Apara&mdash;on the tips of a trident that rises above the enthroned corpse of Sadasiva is intended to express that the Trika has transcended, among other systems, the Saiva Siddhanta. It is noteworthy, however, that we should find not only that the enthronement of the principal deity should be an almost universal feature of tantric cults but also that many elements of the throne are the same or more than coincidentally similar in different systems. The most widespread common feature of thrones is that of a lotus resting upon a <I>pitha</I> that has at least four legs in the intermediate directions, these legs being formed by lions as incarnations of entities that have the names of the four positive qualities of the <I>buddhi</I>, namely, <I>dharma, j&ntilde;ana, vairagya</I> and <I>aisvarya</I>. Furthermore, we find both Saiva and Pa&ntilde;caratra accounts in which the mantras of these entities involve the four so-called &lsquo;neuter&rsquo; vowels. Thus, the rituals of these cults may be shown to express or reinforce doctrinal truths, but we cannot in such cases always assume that their original &lsquo;sense&rsquo; is shining through: expression of doctrine must often rather be the result of successful secondary reinterpretation. Plainly, an examination of thrones furnishes evidence of the kind that led to Sanderson&rsquo;s observation that &lsquo;[t]he ritual systems taught in the Saiva and Pa&ntilde;caratrika Samhitas resemble each other so closely in morphology and syntax that they have the appearance of two dialects of a single "Tantric" language.&rsquo;<sup>4</sup> In this article I will attempt an exploration of some textual accounts of thrones and I hope to provide a &lsquo;footnote&rsquo; to Sanderson&rsquo;s observation, which although is itself part of a footnote, deserves a more prominent place and, of course, examination in not a few further &lsquo;footnotes&rsquo;.</p>
]]></description>
<dc:creator><![CDATA[Goodall, D.]]></dc:creator>
<dc:date>2013-01-23T10:08:20-08:00</dc:date>
<dc:identifier>info:doi/10.1177/0257643012459417</dc:identifier>
<dc:identifier>hwp:resource-id:spsih;27/2/221</dc:identifier>
<dc:title><![CDATA[The Throne of Worship: An 'Archaeological Tell' of Religious Rivalries]]></dc:title>
<prism:publicationDate>2011-08-01</prism:publicationDate>
<prism:section>Articles</prism:section>
<prism:volume>27</prism:volume>
<prism:number>2</prism:number>
<prism:startingPage>221</prism:startingPage>
<prism:endingPage>250</prism:endingPage>
<prism:issueName>Special Issue: The Dynamics of Religious Pluralism: Conflicts, Assimilation and Innovation in Pre-modern India</prism:issueName>
</item>
<item rdf:about="http://sih.sagepub.com/cgi/content/abstract/27/2/251?rss=1">
<title><![CDATA[Cross, Sword and Conflicts: A Study of the Political Meanings of the Struggle between the Padroado Real and the Propaganda Fide]]></title>
<link>http://sih.sagepub.com/cgi/content/abstract/27/2/251?rss=1</link>
<description><![CDATA[
<p>Geographical explorations and the subsequent intensification of external commerce made many political actors of the sixteenth and seventeenth centuries AD drag in religion and its various institutions as pliable devices for strengthening their claims of monopoly and control over the political and commercial life of the newly discovered regions. In the midst of these developments, the pre-colonial struggles for appropriating surplus from the European possessions in Asia were at times in the form of struggles between different religious institutions and administrative machineries within the same belief system professed by the various European powers. These conflicts often arose when some of the religious institutions, which were devised at different points of time in history to transmit various types of spiritual experiences to the believers, were appropriated by power-mongers for realizing their political and economic agenda. One of the religious institutions that were often utilized for political purposes during the early modern period was the church administrative system of patronage or the <I>Patronato</I> that the Spaniards introduced in America and the <I>Padroado Real</I> that the Portuguese set up in Asia. As per the right of patronage that the Pope conceded in AD 1455, the Portuguese Crown became the sole authority that could send missionaries to the lands controlled by the Lusitanians, which eventually created a certain type of monopoly for them in matters of Christianity in areas under their influence and kept missionaries of other nationalities out of Asian and Brazilian soil. When the religious issues in Asia began to get increasingly embroiled in the politics of the times, thanks to the dominance of Lusitanian interests in the <I>Padroado</I> system, Pope Gregory XV devised the <I>Propaganda Fide</I> in AD 1622 as an alternative church administrative system for Asia, which in fact was meant to provide opportunities basically for non-Portuguese people, both Indians and Europeans, for missionary work in Asia. However, this led to a chain of conflicts between the ecclesiastical administrative institutions of the <I>Padroado Real</I> and those of the <I>Propaganda Fide</I>, in Asia in general and India in particular, where the core issues of contestation began to revolve around matters of politics and the exercise of power. The central purpose of this article is to examine the nuanced nature of the conflicts that arose between the church administrative systems of the <I>Padroado</I> and the <I>Propaganda</I> at different points in time and also to see how the religious conflicts were appropriated and politicized by the various European colonial powers to further their politico-economic agenda in India.</p>
]]></description>
<dc:creator><![CDATA[Malekandathil, P.]]></dc:creator>
<dc:date>2013-01-23T10:08:20-08:00</dc:date>
<dc:identifier>info:doi/10.1177/0257643012459418</dc:identifier>
<dc:identifier>hwp:resource-id:spsih;27/2/251</dc:identifier>
<dc:title><![CDATA[Cross, Sword and Conflicts: A Study of the Political Meanings of the Struggle between the Padroado Real and the Propaganda Fide]]></dc:title>
<prism:publicationDate>2011-08-01</prism:publicationDate>
<prism:section>Articles</prism:section>
<prism:volume>27</prism:volume>
<prism:number>2</prism:number>
<prism:startingPage>251</prism:startingPage>
<prism:endingPage>267</prism:endingPage>
<prism:issueName>Special Issue: The Dynamics of Religious Pluralism: Conflicts, Assimilation and Innovation in Pre-modern India</prism:issueName>
</item>
<item rdf:about="http://sih.sagepub.com/cgi/content/abstract/27/2/269?rss=1">
<title><![CDATA[Benevolent Consort or Dangerous Adversary? The Accommodation of the Goddess in the Hymns of the Tamil Saiva Saint Appar]]></title>
<link>http://sih.sagepub.com/cgi/content/abstract/27/2/269?rss=1</link>
<description><![CDATA[
<p>The Tamil Bhakti tradition has variously been understood as a literary efflorescence, religious revival, or an ideological tool through which social tensions were eased. In this article, I highlight the significance of <I>bhakti</I> or devotion as an ideology that transformed the cultural landscape of <I>Tamilakam</I>, through its proponents&rsquo; invocation of the sectarian deities Siva and Visnu. The Saiva saint Appar&rsquo;s <I>patikam</I>, composed between the mid-sixth and mid-seventh century AD, reveals this process in the typical fashion: through the introduction of Siva along with his divine pantheon, the Puranic mythologies, and representations of conflict and accommodation in particular sacred sites. There are many instances where goddesses are invoked as benevolent consorts on the one hand, and as dangerous adversaries on the other. While it is the Brahmanical female deities who are clearly given representation, although in a marginal manner, the choice of specific sites to explicate certain motifs, such as that of a dance contest between the goddess and Siva, indicates the manner in which local goddess traditions and cult spots were appropriated and accommodated within the Brahmanical tradition. As the loving spouse, the goddess is presented as the perfect foil to Siva, while as the aggressive independent female deity she is depicted as his anti-thesis. The goddess may not have been the recipient of Appar&rsquo;s <I>bhakti</I> fervour by herself, but as a result of her engagements with Siva, she was included in the ideational world of devotion.</p>
]]></description>
<dc:creator><![CDATA[Mahalakshmi, R.]]></dc:creator>
<dc:date>2013-01-23T10:08:20-08:00</dc:date>
<dc:identifier>info:doi/10.1177/0257643012459419</dc:identifier>
<dc:identifier>hwp:resource-id:spsih;27/2/269</dc:identifier>
<dc:title><![CDATA[Benevolent Consort or Dangerous Adversary? The Accommodation of the Goddess in the Hymns of the Tamil Saiva Saint Appar]]></dc:title>
<prism:publicationDate>2011-08-01</prism:publicationDate>
<prism:section>Articles</prism:section>
<prism:volume>27</prism:volume>
<prism:number>2</prism:number>
<prism:startingPage>269</prism:startingPage>
<prism:endingPage>279</prism:endingPage>
<prism:issueName>Special Issue: The Dynamics of Religious Pluralism: Conflicts, Assimilation and Innovation in Pre-modern India</prism:issueName>
</item>
<item rdf:about="http://sih.sagepub.com/cgi/content/abstract/27/2/281?rss=1">
<title><![CDATA[Beyond the Archives: Doing Oral History in Contemporary India]]></title>
<link>http://sih.sagepub.com/cgi/content/abstract/27/2/281?rss=1</link>
<description><![CDATA[
<p>This article on extending the archive beyond its traditional avatar is intended for the researcher and enthusiast in contemporary history, those doing oral history and students and teachers offering courses in historical method.1 The process that I wish to highlight is the movement of historical study and research beyond the confines of the written archives, away from the official records, to the village chaupals and fields of the peasants, to the offices of trade unions, to factory canteens, to simple homes, where people gather, meet and live their lives. I discuss one such trend, namely, oral history, which has energized the field of history. In the second part of the article, I take a close look at two oral history initiatives to explore issues of methodology and ethics, as well as the transformative aspects of the exercise. The first is the project (of which I was a member) sponsored by the Indian Council of Social Science Research on the history of the freedom movement, conducted by professors and researchers at the Jawaharlal Nehru University (JNU); and the second, testimonies of the survivors/victims of the Partition recorded by researchers.</p>
]]></description>
<dc:creator><![CDATA[Mahajan, S.]]></dc:creator>
<dc:date>2013-01-23T10:08:20-08:00</dc:date>
<dc:identifier>info:doi/10.1177/0257643012459422</dc:identifier>
<dc:identifier>hwp:resource-id:spsih;27/2/281</dc:identifier>
<dc:title><![CDATA[Beyond the Archives: Doing Oral History in Contemporary India]]></dc:title>
<prism:publicationDate>2011-08-01</prism:publicationDate>
<prism:section>Archive</prism:section>
<prism:volume>27</prism:volume>
<prism:number>2</prism:number>
<prism:startingPage>281</prism:startingPage>
<prism:endingPage>298</prism:endingPage>
<prism:issueName>Special Issue: The Dynamics of Religious Pluralism: Conflicts, Assimilation and Innovation in Pre-modern India</prism:issueName>
</item>
<item rdf:about="http://sih.sagepub.com/cgi/content/abstract/27/1/1?rss=1">
<title><![CDATA[When Kannaki Was Given a Voice]]></title>
<link>http://sih.sagepub.com/cgi/content/abstract/27/1/1?rss=1</link>
<description><![CDATA[
<p>When ancient stories are retold for a new readership in contemporary times, subtle changes are made that reflect on society. Through the early decades of the twentieth century, the story of Kannaki, the heroine of the epic <I>Silappatikaram</I>, was retold several times in prose and as plays. The Kannaki of the <I>Silappatikaram</I> is vastly different from the Kannaki of the plays. For one, in many of the plays, Kannaki speaks much more than she was allowed to in the epic work by Ilango Adigal. This article is an attempt to understand the &lsquo;silence&rsquo; of Kannaki in the epic and the &lsquo;voice&rsquo; of Kannaki in one of the early plays by Nagai C. Gopala Krishna Pillai written in the social reform context of early twentieth-century Madras Presidency.</p>
]]></description>
<dc:creator><![CDATA[Rani, P.]]></dc:creator>
<dc:date>2012-01-10T09:02:17-08:00</dc:date>
<dc:identifier>info:doi/10.1177/025764301102700101</dc:identifier>
<dc:identifier>hwp:resource-id:spsih;27/1/1</dc:identifier>
<dc:title><![CDATA[When Kannaki Was Given a Voice]]></dc:title>
<prism:publicationDate>2011-02-01</prism:publicationDate>
<prism:section>Articles</prism:section>
<prism:volume>27</prism:volume>
<prism:number>1</prism:number>
<prism:startingPage>1</prism:startingPage>
<prism:endingPage>20</prism:endingPage>
</item>
<item rdf:about="http://sih.sagepub.com/cgi/content/abstract/27/1/21?rss=1">
<title><![CDATA[The Dharmapada Tradition Revisited]]></title>
<link>http://sih.sagepub.com/cgi/content/abstract/27/1/21?rss=1</link>
<description><![CDATA[
<p>The traditional account of Dharmapada represents the identity consciousness of the Oriyas from the middle of the nineteenth century to the first phase of the twentieth century by repudiating the charge that the Oriya people could not make or complete the stupendous Konarka temple and that they did not possess such masterly skill. When the past is not properly seen, and so denied, in the present, traditional accounts help in articulating the past. The traditional account of Dharmapada is a significant example of the connection between the distant and hard-to-believe past and the present. The tradition from the 1930s onwards asserted the social and cultural identity of the Oriyas. It was appropriated from a different context, the Samba Purana, and had many phases of construction. The Dharmapada tradition forms a significant part of the common artistic tradition of South India (which has been presented in this article in the contexts of the temples of Belur and Simhachalam). No doubt the major aim of the formation of this account in the beginning was to assert the fact of completion of the stupendous temple of Konarka by the artisans of Orissa. However, from the nationalist phase of the 1920s, it was reconstructed to mobilize the young men and women of Orissa. Young, self-sacrificing Oriya men and women were needed for the new Orissa-in-the-making, and the Dharmapada tradition of this phase accordingly highlighted the spirit of self-sacrifice. The efforts of the Oriya nationalists to inspire the Oriya youth in the first two decades of the twentieth century found an interesting finishing point in the Dharmapada tradition, which is now accepted as an unmistakable marker of Oriya identity, just like the Jagannatha cult.</p>
]]></description>
<dc:creator><![CDATA[Kailash Chandra, D.]]></dc:creator>
<dc:date>2012-01-10T09:02:18-08:00</dc:date>
<dc:identifier>info:doi/10.1177/025764301102700102</dc:identifier>
<dc:identifier>hwp:resource-id:spsih;27/1/21</dc:identifier>
<dc:title><![CDATA[The Dharmapada Tradition Revisited]]></dc:title>
<prism:publicationDate>2011-02-01</prism:publicationDate>
<prism:section>Articles</prism:section>
<prism:volume>27</prism:volume>
<prism:number>1</prism:number>
<prism:startingPage>21</prism:startingPage>
<prism:endingPage>40</prism:endingPage>
</item>
<item rdf:about="http://sih.sagepub.com/cgi/content/abstract/27/1/41?rss=1">
<title><![CDATA[Women Performers and Prostitutes in Medieval India]]></title>
<link>http://sih.sagepub.com/cgi/content/abstract/27/1/41?rss=1</link>
<description><![CDATA[
<p>Music and dance, the esoteric performing arts, were markers of culture in medieval India. A number of these differing forms developed into well-recognized and reputed arts over time. The practitioners were, accordingly, regarded as agents of refinement and culture. At the same time, music and dance were also among the most popular forms of entertainment and physical pleasure. This aspect remained crucial in classifying musicians, singers and dancers as entertainers, alongside prostitutes. While the labelling together might have reduced the status of performers at times, the labelling hardly remained fixed. Certain practitioners, even if involved in practices otherwise considered immoral, could remain within the elite circle, while for others the &lsquo;evil&rsquo; characteristics got emphasized. There were, within the class of women who prostituted themselves, courtesans trained in the skills of music and dancing and educated in the fine arts, who were treated more as embodiments of culture. These categories&mdash;artists, skilled entertainers, courtesans&mdash;were quite fluid, with the boundaries seemingly fused together. Still, there were certainly some distinctions among the categories and those did not totally disappear, affording sanctity and purity to certain kinds of performers and allowing them to claim distinctiveness. Notably, the class of courtesans clearly stood apart from the common prostitutes. The attempt in this article is to look at different categories of women performers and prostitutes, their apparent coalescing boundaries and specialities as a separate group, their societal position, their shifting roles and the changes that affected their status. In this, it is worthwhile to consider the state&rsquo;s attitude towards them, besides societal views that remained quite diverse.</p>
]]></description>
<dc:creator><![CDATA[Bano, S.]]></dc:creator>
<dc:date>2012-01-10T09:02:18-08:00</dc:date>
<dc:identifier>info:doi/10.1177/025764301102700103</dc:identifier>
<dc:identifier>hwp:resource-id:spsih;27/1/41</dc:identifier>
<dc:title><![CDATA[Women Performers and Prostitutes in Medieval India]]></dc:title>
<prism:publicationDate>2011-02-01</prism:publicationDate>
<prism:section>Articles</prism:section>
<prism:volume>27</prism:volume>
<prism:number>1</prism:number>
<prism:startingPage>41</prism:startingPage>
<prism:endingPage>53</prism:endingPage>
</item>
<item rdf:about="http://sih.sagepub.com/cgi/content/abstract/27/1/55?rss=1">
<title><![CDATA[European Mercenaries in the Indian Armies:                AD 1750-1803]]></title>
<link>http://sih.sagepub.com/cgi/content/abstract/27/1/55?rss=1</link>
<description><![CDATA[
<p>The eclipse of Mughal power as the central authority began from the second half of the seventeenth century. By the time of the eighteenth century, and particularly from its second half, the local potentates began to empower themselves to defend as well as to expand their power. For this, they resorted to strengthen their armed forces. Thus, they employed Europeans as mercenaries in their armies. These mercenaries were considered superior in artillery and better in organizing the militia. Their interests also affected the colonial powers. In this article, the social and geographical background of the mercenaries has been discussed. An important part of the study is their role in the armies of their employers. The salaries and perquisites received by them have been taken into account. These payments were an additional channel of drainage of Indian wealth to Europe.</p>
]]></description>
<dc:creator><![CDATA[A. Zaidi, S. I.]]></dc:creator>
<dc:date>2012-01-10T09:02:18-08:00</dc:date>
<dc:identifier>info:doi/10.1177/025764301102700104</dc:identifier>
<dc:identifier>hwp:resource-id:spsih;27/1/55</dc:identifier>
<dc:title><![CDATA[European Mercenaries in the Indian Armies:                AD 1750-1803]]></dc:title>
<prism:publicationDate>2011-02-01</prism:publicationDate>
<prism:section>Articles</prism:section>
<prism:volume>27</prism:volume>
<prism:number>1</prism:number>
<prism:startingPage>55</prism:startingPage>
<prism:endingPage>83</prism:endingPage>
</item>
<item rdf:about="http://sih.sagepub.com/cgi/content/abstract/27/1/85?rss=1">
<title><![CDATA[Collecting Objects: Situating the Indian Collection (1884-1945) in Pitt Rivers Museum, Oxford]]></title>
<link>http://sih.sagepub.com/cgi/content/abstract/27/1/85?rss=1</link>
<description><![CDATA[
<p>The second half of the nineteenth century witnessed an enhanced role for museums in Great Britain. There was also a parallel growth in private collections and an eagerness to collect souvenirs from distant lands. Material culture emerged as an important means to understand the evolutionary history of humankind. The development of archaeology and anthropology may be situated in this backdrop. The Pitt Rivers Museum in Oxford was founded in 1884 with a founding collection of archaeological and ethnographic objects from around the world. The donor was Augustus Henry Lane Fox, better known as Col. Pitt Rivers. The Indian collection of archaeological objects, amassed over the succeeding years, forms the subject of this article. I attempt to show how the colony and the metropolis were tied in a broad network of connections. I also argue that this enterprise of &lsquo;collecting&rsquo;&mdash;participated in by colonial servants, missionaries and others&mdash;lent an important dimension to the beginning of prehistoric research in the subcontinent.</p>
]]></description>
<dc:creator><![CDATA[Basak, B.]]></dc:creator>
<dc:date>2012-01-10T09:02:18-08:00</dc:date>
<dc:identifier>info:doi/10.1177/025764301102700105</dc:identifier>
<dc:identifier>hwp:resource-id:spsih;27/1/85</dc:identifier>
<dc:title><![CDATA[Collecting Objects: Situating the Indian Collection (1884-1945) in Pitt Rivers Museum, Oxford]]></dc:title>
<prism:publicationDate>2011-02-01</prism:publicationDate>
<prism:section>Articles</prism:section>
<prism:volume>27</prism:volume>
<prism:number>1</prism:number>
<prism:startingPage>85</prism:startingPage>
<prism:endingPage>109</prism:endingPage>
</item>
<item rdf:about="http://sih.sagepub.com/cgi/content/abstract/27/1/111?rss=1">
<title><![CDATA[Gandhi, Dinabandhu and Din-sevak: Critical Solidarity from Two Anglican Missionaries]]></title>
<link>http://sih.sagepub.com/cgi/content/abstract/27/1/111?rss=1</link>
<description><![CDATA[
<p>Despite Anglican Christianity&rsquo;s frequent close association with the state, there have always been some, inspired by Christianity&rsquo;s founder, who have taken a more independent line, none more strikingly so than two English missionaries in India, C.F. Andrews and Verrier Elwin, who broke with prevailing loyalties and in the strength of profound friendships with Gandhi, identified with Indian interests and nationalist aspirations during the half century prior to Indian Independence.</p>
]]></description>
<dc:creator><![CDATA[O'Connor, D.]]></dc:creator>
<dc:date>2012-01-10T09:02:18-08:00</dc:date>
<dc:identifier>info:doi/10.1177/025764301102700106</dc:identifier>
<dc:identifier>hwp:resource-id:spsih;27/1/111</dc:identifier>
<dc:title><![CDATA[Gandhi, Dinabandhu and Din-sevak: Critical Solidarity from Two Anglican Missionaries]]></dc:title>
<prism:publicationDate>2011-02-01</prism:publicationDate>
<prism:section>Articles</prism:section>
<prism:volume>27</prism:volume>
<prism:number>1</prism:number>
<prism:startingPage>111</prism:startingPage>
<prism:endingPage>129</prism:endingPage>
</item>
<item rdf:about="http://sih.sagepub.com/cgi/reprint/27/1/131?rss=1">
<title><![CDATA[Book Review: People, Taxation and Trade in Mughal India]]></title>
<link>http://sih.sagepub.com/cgi/reprint/27/1/131?rss=1</link>
<description><![CDATA[]]></description>
<dc:creator><![CDATA[Mukherjee, A.]]></dc:creator>
<dc:date>2012-01-10T09:02:18-08:00</dc:date>
<dc:identifier>info:doi/10.1177/025764301102700107</dc:identifier>
<dc:identifier>hwp:resource-id:spsih;27/1/131</dc:identifier>
<dc:title><![CDATA[Book Review: People, Taxation and Trade in Mughal India]]></dc:title>
<prism:publicationDate>2011-02-01</prism:publicationDate>
<prism:section>Book Reviews</prism:section>
<prism:volume>27</prism:volume>
<prism:number>1</prism:number>
<prism:startingPage>131</prism:startingPage>
<prism:endingPage>133</prism:endingPage>
</item>
<item rdf:about="http://sih.sagepub.com/cgi/reprint/27/1/133?rss=1">
<title><![CDATA[Book Review: The Indian Uprising of 1857-58: Prisons, Prisoners and Rebellion]]></title>
<link>http://sih.sagepub.com/cgi/reprint/27/1/133?rss=1</link>
<description><![CDATA[]]></description>
<dc:creator><![CDATA[Dasgupta, S.]]></dc:creator>
<dc:date>2012-01-10T09:02:18-08:00</dc:date>
<dc:identifier>info:doi/10.1177/025764301102700108</dc:identifier>
<dc:identifier>hwp:resource-id:spsih;27/1/133</dc:identifier>
<dc:title><![CDATA[Book Review: The Indian Uprising of 1857-58: Prisons, Prisoners and Rebellion]]></dc:title>
<prism:publicationDate>2011-02-01</prism:publicationDate>
<prism:section>Book Reviews</prism:section>
<prism:volume>27</prism:volume>
<prism:number>1</prism:number>
<prism:startingPage>133</prism:startingPage>
<prism:endingPage>135</prism:endingPage>
</item>
<item rdf:about="http://sih.sagepub.com/cgi/reprint/27/1/136?rss=1">
<title><![CDATA[Book Review: Peasants in India's Non-violent Revolution: Practice and Theory and Colonizing Agriculture: The Myth of Punjab Exceptionalism]]></title>
<link>http://sih.sagepub.com/cgi/reprint/27/1/136?rss=1</link>
<description><![CDATA[]]></description>
<dc:creator><![CDATA[Banerjee, H.]]></dc:creator>
<dc:date>2012-01-10T09:02:18-08:00</dc:date>
<dc:identifier>info:doi/10.1177/025764301102700109</dc:identifier>
<dc:identifier>hwp:resource-id:spsih;27/1/136</dc:identifier>
<dc:title><![CDATA[Book Review: Peasants in India's Non-violent Revolution: Practice and Theory and Colonizing Agriculture: The Myth of Punjab Exceptionalism]]></dc:title>
<prism:publicationDate>2011-02-01</prism:publicationDate>
<prism:section>Book Reviews</prism:section>
<prism:volume>27</prism:volume>
<prism:number>1</prism:number>
<prism:startingPage>136</prism:startingPage>
<prism:endingPage>141</prism:endingPage>
</item>
<item rdf:about="http://sih.sagepub.com/cgi/reprint/27/1/141?rss=1">
<title><![CDATA[Book Review: Theatre of Conflict, City of Hope: Mumbai 1600 to Present Times]]></title>
<link>http://sih.sagepub.com/cgi/reprint/27/1/141?rss=1</link>
<description><![CDATA[]]></description>
<dc:creator><![CDATA[Krishan, S.]]></dc:creator>
<dc:date>2012-01-10T09:02:18-08:00</dc:date>
<dc:identifier>info:doi/10.1177/025764301102700110</dc:identifier>
<dc:identifier>hwp:resource-id:spsih;27/1/141</dc:identifier>
<dc:title><![CDATA[Book Review: Theatre of Conflict, City of Hope: Mumbai 1600 to Present Times]]></dc:title>
<prism:publicationDate>2011-02-01</prism:publicationDate>
<prism:section>Book Reviews</prism:section>
<prism:volume>27</prism:volume>
<prism:number>1</prism:number>
<prism:startingPage>141</prism:startingPage>
<prism:endingPage>146</prism:endingPage>
</item>
<item rdf:about="http://sih.sagepub.com/cgi/content/abstract/27/1/147?rss=1">
<title><![CDATA[Erratum]]></title>
<link>http://sih.sagepub.com/cgi/content/abstract/27/1/147?rss=1</link>
<description><![CDATA[
<p>Pritish Acharya, <I>National Movement and Politics in Orissa, 1920&ndash;29</I> (Sage Series in Modern Indian History&ndash;XI), Sage Publications India Pvt. Ltd, New Delhi, 2008, pp. 301,  595.</p>
<p>By Shri Krishan, Senior Fellow, Nehru Memorial Museum and Library, New Delhi</p>
<p>This book review has been inadvertently published both in SIH 26.1 (February 2010 issue, original DOI: 10.1177/025764301002600105) and SIH 26.2 (August 2010 issue, original DOI: 10.1177/025764301002600207).</p>
]]></description>
<dc:creator><![CDATA[]]></dc:creator>
<dc:date>2012-01-10T09:02:18-08:00</dc:date>
<dc:identifier>info:doi/10.1177/025764301102700111</dc:identifier>
<dc:identifier>hwp:resource-id:spsih;27/1/147</dc:identifier>
<dc:title><![CDATA[Erratum]]></dc:title>
<prism:publicationDate>2011-02-01</prism:publicationDate>
<prism:section>Articles</prism:section>
<prism:volume>27</prism:volume>
<prism:number>1</prism:number>
<prism:startingPage>147</prism:startingPage>
<prism:endingPage>147</prism:endingPage>
</item>
<item rdf:about="http://sih.sagepub.com/cgi/content/abstract/26/2/103?rss=1">
<title><![CDATA[Land Acquisition for the Railways in Bengal, 1850-62: Probing a Contemporary Problem]]></title>
<link>http://sih.sagepub.com/cgi/content/abstract/26/2/103?rss=1</link>
<description><![CDATA[
<p>This article on the acquisition of land for the railways in Bengal, during the most formative phase of their construction in India, rejects the dominant notion of the trouble-free transfer of land. It examines the legal and social issues involved in acquiring land for public works. Based on the analysis of cases of both the individual and the village based reactions, the article suggests that the opposition to the land acquisition drive for early railways in Bengal had been both location and class specific. The intensity of the opposition sometimes forced the government of the East India Company to change the original route map of the railways. The people, Indian and European alike, were opposed mainly to the government&rsquo;s policy of undervaluation of land and the uniform rate of compensation. In the post-1857 period, the speedy extension of the railways became a priority for the new government. Nevertheless, far from hardening its stand on land acquisition, British government adopted a conciliatory and more sensitive attitude to this contentious issue. The realignment of railroad, exclusion of sacred sites, location specific valuation of land and the policy of liberal compensation, discussed in this study, are all important evidence of this flexibility.</p>
]]></description>
<dc:creator><![CDATA[Sarkar, S.]]></dc:creator>
<dc:date>2011-03-28T10:02:49-07:00</dc:date>
<dc:identifier>info:doi/10.1177/025764301002600201</dc:identifier>
<dc:identifier>hwp:resource-id:spsih;26/2/103</dc:identifier>
<dc:title><![CDATA[Land Acquisition for the Railways in Bengal, 1850-62: Probing a Contemporary Problem]]></dc:title>
<prism:publicationDate>2010-08-01</prism:publicationDate>
<prism:section>Articles</prism:section>
<prism:volume>26</prism:volume>
<prism:number>2</prism:number>
<prism:startingPage>103</prism:startingPage>
<prism:endingPage>142</prism:endingPage>
</item>
<item rdf:about="http://sih.sagepub.com/cgi/content/abstract/26/2/143?rss=1">
<title><![CDATA[Schooling 'Truant' Tribes: British Colonial Compulsions and Educational Evolution in Chhotanagpur, 1870-1930]]></title>
<link>http://sih.sagepub.com/cgi/content/abstract/26/2/143?rss=1</link>
<description><![CDATA[
<p>British colonial education in India, promoted under the policy frame of &lsquo;filteration&rsquo;, barely reached the remote recesses of the empire. Permeation was sluggish and growth uneven. A case in point would be the tribal hinterland of Chhotanagpur in Bengal province. This article shows that while parts of Bengal led colonial India in educational growth, places like Chhotanagpur, in stark contrast to centres such as Calcutta, remained largely untouched. This, despite the fact, that the system was introduced as early as 1839 (as a local project at the behest of the concerned official) in Chhotanagpur. Not only that, the system so introduced also received considerable impetus in the late nineteenth and early twentieth century from the colonial agenda of &lsquo;civilizing&rsquo; the &lsquo;barbarians&rsquo;. For this task, the government usually relied upon the services of missionaries. The efforts of the missionaries, their humanitarian attitude toward the tribals notwithstanding, were ineluctably marred by the constraints of their mission field and prejudiced missionary paradigm. Owing to which, the missionaries were unable to devise a pro-tribal educational policy, thus leading to the tribals receiving the faulty system on their own terms. While the tribals valorized certain aspects of the system, they were, unlike elsewhere, unable to further develop the system through indigenous initiative.</p>
]]></description>
<dc:creator><![CDATA[Bara, J.]]></dc:creator>
<dc:date>2011-03-28T10:02:49-07:00</dc:date>
<dc:identifier>info:doi/10.1177/025764301002600202</dc:identifier>
<dc:identifier>hwp:resource-id:spsih;26/2/143</dc:identifier>
<dc:title><![CDATA[Schooling 'Truant' Tribes: British Colonial Compulsions and Educational Evolution in Chhotanagpur, 1870-1930]]></dc:title>
<prism:publicationDate>2010-08-01</prism:publicationDate>
<prism:section>Articles</prism:section>
<prism:volume>26</prism:volume>
<prism:number>2</prism:number>
<prism:startingPage>143</prism:startingPage>
<prism:endingPage>173</prism:endingPage>
</item>
<item rdf:about="http://sih.sagepub.com/cgi/content/abstract/26/2/175?rss=1">
<title><![CDATA[Landlords, Tenants and Agrarian Relations: Revisiting a Peasant Uprising in Colonial Assam]]></title>
<link>http://sih.sagepub.com/cgi/content/abstract/26/2/175?rss=1</link>
<description><![CDATA[
<p>This article re-examines the social history of a widely discussed peasant uprising in colonial Assam. Drawing on extensive archival sources, the article examines how peasants who came under increasing taxation reacted to the revenue enhancement. The article explores the role played by the Assamese landlords in giving leadership to the peasant dissatisfaction. It shows how the landlords&rsquo; specific interest has been masked by the existing historiography. The article unfolds the complex layers of social interests which came to play their critical role in creating the events of 1894.</p>
]]></description>
<dc:creator><![CDATA[Saikia, A.]]></dc:creator>
<dc:date>2011-03-28T10:02:49-07:00</dc:date>
<dc:identifier>info:doi/10.1177/025764301002600203</dc:identifier>
<dc:identifier>hwp:resource-id:spsih;26/2/175</dc:identifier>
<dc:title><![CDATA[Landlords, Tenants and Agrarian Relations: Revisiting a Peasant Uprising in Colonial Assam]]></dc:title>
<prism:publicationDate>2010-08-01</prism:publicationDate>
<prism:section>Articles</prism:section>
<prism:volume>26</prism:volume>
<prism:number>2</prism:number>
<prism:startingPage>175</prism:startingPage>
<prism:endingPage>209</prism:endingPage>
</item>
<item rdf:about="http://sih.sagepub.com/cgi/content/abstract/26/2/211?rss=1">
<title><![CDATA[Music in the Himalayas: Alexander Scriabin and the Spiritual]]></title>
<link>http://sih.sagepub.com/cgi/content/abstract/26/2/211?rss=1</link>
<description><![CDATA[
<p>This article is part of a larger project on music, painting and the spiritual in twentieth century Continental Europe. From 1901 to his premature death, Alexander Scriabin was obsessed with his project, the Mysterium, an apocalyptic event, set preferably in the Himalayas, and all his music is by preparation for its fulfilment. The methodology followed in this article is to set Scriabin in his biographical, political, cultural and philosophical context, before exploring his comparatively small musical output.</p>
]]></description>
<dc:creator><![CDATA[Copley, A.]]></dc:creator>
<dc:date>2011-03-28T10:02:49-07:00</dc:date>
<dc:identifier>info:doi/10.1177/025764301002600204</dc:identifier>
<dc:identifier>hwp:resource-id:spsih;26/2/211</dc:identifier>
<dc:title><![CDATA[Music in the Himalayas: Alexander Scriabin and the Spiritual]]></dc:title>
<prism:publicationDate>2010-08-01</prism:publicationDate>
<prism:section>Articles</prism:section>
<prism:volume>26</prism:volume>
<prism:number>2</prism:number>
<prism:startingPage>211</prism:startingPage>
<prism:endingPage>226</prism:endingPage>
</item>
<item rdf:about="http://sih.sagepub.com/cgi/content/abstract/26/2/227?rss=1">
<title><![CDATA[Blaming the Brahmins: Texts Lost and Found in Tamil Literary History]]></title>
<link>http://sih.sagepub.com/cgi/content/abstract/26/2/227?rss=1</link>
<description><![CDATA[
<p>Tamil literary history abounds in legends about texts lost and found. The theme resurfaces in modern literary history in descriptions of the rediscovery of classical Can.kam poetry at the end of the nineteenth century. If this poetic corpus has never been literally lost but has merely been invisible, circulating in the small circle of scholars, it is said to have been kept away by brahmins from its rightful owner, the Tamil people. Instead, the brahmins forced their own Sanskrit texts upon the Tamils. Curiously, this scenario, which is clearly indebted to the political idiom of the Dravidian movement, finds its most explicit expression in the works of two scholars, A.K. Ramanujan and K.V. Zvelebil, who, contary to their colleagues, past and present, working in Tamil Nadu itself, could easily have ignored any form of pressure from the political side. At the same time, both were men with strong literary ambitions, who as such have been carried away by literary fancy itself.</p>
]]></description>
<dc:creator><![CDATA[Tieken, H.]]></dc:creator>
<dc:date>2011-03-28T10:02:49-07:00</dc:date>
<dc:identifier>info:doi/10.1177/025764301002600205</dc:identifier>
<dc:identifier>hwp:resource-id:spsih;26/2/227</dc:identifier>
<dc:title><![CDATA[Blaming the Brahmins: Texts Lost and Found in Tamil Literary History]]></dc:title>
<prism:publicationDate>2010-08-01</prism:publicationDate>
<prism:section>Articles</prism:section>
<prism:volume>26</prism:volume>
<prism:number>2</prism:number>
<prism:startingPage>227</prism:startingPage>
<prism:endingPage>243</prism:endingPage>
</item>
<item rdf:about="http://sih.sagepub.com/cgi/reprint/26/2/245?rss=1">
<title><![CDATA[Parul Pandya Dhar, The Torana in Indian and Southeast Asian Architecture, D.K. Printworld, Delhi, 2009, pp. xii-xvii, 317, Rs 4200]]></title>
<link>http://sih.sagepub.com/cgi/reprint/26/2/245?rss=1</link>
<description><![CDATA[]]></description>
<dc:creator><![CDATA[Mahalakshmi, R.]]></dc:creator>
<dc:date>2011-03-28T10:02:49-07:00</dc:date>
<dc:identifier>info:doi/10.1177/025764301002600206</dc:identifier>
<dc:identifier>hwp:resource-id:spsih;26/2/245</dc:identifier>
<dc:title><![CDATA[Parul Pandya Dhar, The Torana in Indian and Southeast Asian Architecture, D.K. Printworld, Delhi, 2009, pp. xii-xvii, 317, Rs 4200]]></dc:title>
<prism:publicationDate>2010-08-01</prism:publicationDate>
<prism:section>Articles</prism:section>
<prism:volume>26</prism:volume>
<prism:number>2</prism:number>
<prism:startingPage>245</prism:startingPage>
<prism:endingPage>249</prism:endingPage>
</item>
<item rdf:about="http://sih.sagepub.com/cgi/reprint/26/2/250?rss=1">
<title><![CDATA[Pritish Acharya, National Movement and Politics in Orissa, 1920-29 (Sage Series in Modern Indian History-XI), Sage Publications India Pvt. Ltd., New Delhi, 2008, pp. 301, Rs 595]]></title>
<link>http://sih.sagepub.com/cgi/reprint/26/2/250?rss=1</link>
<description><![CDATA[]]></description>
<dc:creator><![CDATA[Krishan, S.]]></dc:creator>
<dc:date>2011-03-28T10:02:49-07:00</dc:date>
<dc:identifier>info:doi/10.1177/025764301002600207</dc:identifier>
<dc:identifier>hwp:resource-id:spsih;26/2/250</dc:identifier>
<dc:title><![CDATA[Pritish Acharya, National Movement and Politics in Orissa, 1920-29 (Sage Series in Modern Indian History-XI), Sage Publications India Pvt. Ltd., New Delhi, 2008, pp. 301, Rs 595]]></dc:title>
<prism:publicationDate>2010-08-01</prism:publicationDate>
<prism:section>Articles</prism:section>
<prism:volume>26</prism:volume>
<prism:number>2</prism:number>
<prism:startingPage>250</prism:startingPage>
<prism:endingPage>254</prism:endingPage>
</item>
<item rdf:about="http://sih.sagepub.com/cgi/reprint/26/2/254?rss=1">
<title><![CDATA[Antony Copley, Gay Writers in Search of the Divine: Hinduism and Homo-sexuality in the Lives and Writings of Edward Carpenter, E.M. Forster and Christopher Isherwood, Yoda Press, New Delhi, 2006]]></title>
<link>http://sih.sagepub.com/cgi/reprint/26/2/254?rss=1</link>
<description><![CDATA[]]></description>
<dc:creator><![CDATA[Visvanathan, S.]]></dc:creator>
<dc:date>2011-03-28T10:02:49-07:00</dc:date>
<dc:identifier>info:doi/10.1177/025764301002600208</dc:identifier>
<dc:identifier>hwp:resource-id:spsih;26/2/254</dc:identifier>
<dc:title><![CDATA[Antony Copley, Gay Writers in Search of the Divine: Hinduism and Homo-sexuality in the Lives and Writings of Edward Carpenter, E.M. Forster and Christopher Isherwood, Yoda Press, New Delhi, 2006]]></dc:title>
<prism:publicationDate>2010-08-01</prism:publicationDate>
<prism:section>Articles</prism:section>
<prism:volume>26</prism:volume>
<prism:number>2</prism:number>
<prism:startingPage>254</prism:startingPage>
<prism:endingPage>255</prism:endingPage>
</item>
<item rdf:about="http://sih.sagepub.com/cgi/content/abstract/26/1/1?rss=1">
<title><![CDATA[Yoni, Yoginis and Mahavidyas: Feminine Divinities from Early Medieval Kamarupa to Medieval Koch Behar]]></title>
<link>http://sih.sagepub.com/cgi/content/abstract/26/1/1?rss=1</link>
<description><![CDATA[
<p>Focusing on one of the most prominent sacred sites of goddess(es) worship in India, the Nilacala (blue hill) of Guwahati in Assam, this article delineates the historical evolution of a local goddess cult and its association with the groups of multiple feminine deities. Based on literary, inscriptional, archeological and oral sources, it demonstrates three phases of transition amidst political changes: (i) worship of yoni, the local sacred geography, by autochthonous people, (ii) the reorganized Tantric yogini cult associated with a new regional goddess, who was worshipped by the ruling family of the Mlecchas and the Palas and ( iii) the magical and comprehensive Mahavidyas and the restored goddess Kamakhya cult by the Koches. Here the transition does not mean a sudden change, but a steady process by which a former tradition not only altered but also continued and acquired new connotation in a different socio-religious context. Instead of applying the analytical distinction which often simplifies the multi-sided and prevalent traditions in the form of binary opposition such as &lsquo;tribal/Hindu&rsquo; or &lsquo;local/universal&rsquo; or &lsquo;Tantric/Puranic&rsquo;, this article shows how the divergent strands of incompatible religious traditions became mutually dependent.</p>
]]></description>
<dc:creator><![CDATA[Shin, J.-E.]]></dc:creator>
<dc:date>2011-02-14T03:21:36-08:00</dc:date>
<dc:identifier>info:doi/10.1177/025764301002600101</dc:identifier>
<dc:identifier>hwp:resource-id:spsih;26/1/1</dc:identifier>
<dc:title><![CDATA[Yoni, Yoginis and Mahavidyas: Feminine Divinities from Early Medieval Kamarupa to Medieval Koch Behar]]></dc:title>
<prism:publicationDate>2010-02-01</prism:publicationDate>
<prism:section>Articles</prism:section>
<prism:volume>26</prism:volume>
<prism:number>1</prism:number>
<prism:startingPage>1</prism:startingPage>
<prism:endingPage>29</prism:endingPage>
</item>
<item rdf:about="http://sih.sagepub.com/cgi/content/abstract/26/1/31?rss=1">
<title><![CDATA[Meaning of Work in Dalit Autobiographies]]></title>
<link>http://sih.sagepub.com/cgi/content/abstract/26/1/31?rss=1</link>
<description><![CDATA[
<p>There have been varying perceptions of manual labour in different societies, cultures and thought systems. However, in most pre-modern stratified societies, manual work was considered demeaning. In pre-colonial India, despite various dissenting traditions and protest movements, the dominant ideology continued to privilege non-manual work while degrading manual labour. Thus, the Dalits, most of whom were poor manual workers, remained at the receiving end of this ideology. The colonial regime, owing to its peculiar inherent contradictions, created a dual labour regime for the Dalits whereby their subjection was further strengthened in the rural areas while they experienced some measure of freedom in the cities. The consequent contradictory experiences gave impetus to Dalit movements which sharply attacked the caste system. The Dalit autobiographies emerged in the post-independence period as the most important component of Dalit literature which was a product of the Dalit movement. This article endeavours to analyze some of these texts for their explicit and underlying ideas and notions about work.</p>
]]></description>
<dc:creator><![CDATA[Upadhyay, S. B.]]></dc:creator>
<dc:date>2011-02-14T03:21:36-08:00</dc:date>
<dc:identifier>info:doi/10.1177/025764301002600102</dc:identifier>
<dc:identifier>hwp:resource-id:spsih;26/1/31</dc:identifier>
<dc:title><![CDATA[Meaning of Work in Dalit Autobiographies]]></dc:title>
<prism:publicationDate>2010-02-01</prism:publicationDate>
<prism:section>Articles</prism:section>
<prism:volume>26</prism:volume>
<prism:number>1</prism:number>
<prism:startingPage>31</prism:startingPage>
<prism:endingPage>60</prism:endingPage>
</item>
<item rdf:about="http://sih.sagepub.com/cgi/content/abstract/26/1/61?rss=1">
<title><![CDATA[Housing Shortage and Communal Politics in European Cities around 1900: The Cases of Basel 1889 and Belgrade 1906]]></title>
<link>http://sih.sagepub.com/cgi/content/abstract/26/1/61?rss=1</link>
<description><![CDATA[
<p>In the second half of the nineteenth century, European cities faced a problem well known in postindependence India: the population escalated due to immigration from the rural areas causing rapid and considerable housing shortage. This forced large parts of the poorer classes into miserable living conditions. Lack of space, money and hygiene facilitated the epidemic spread of diseases such as tuberculosis and diarrhoea. The town authorities were called upon to stop speculation and to launch state financed housing projects. However, in reality the situation was very different depending on the place, political aims and financial possibilities arising out of the particular crisis. This article discusses the issue in two continental European cities of around 100,000 inhabitants. The Swiss town of Basel was a hub of trade in Central Europe, while Belgrade was the capital of the Southeastern European kingdom of Serbia.</p>
]]></description>
<dc:creator><![CDATA[Miskovic, N.]]></dc:creator>
<dc:date>2011-02-14T03:21:36-08:00</dc:date>
<dc:identifier>info:doi/10.1177/025764301002600103</dc:identifier>
<dc:identifier>hwp:resource-id:spsih;26/1/61</dc:identifier>
<dc:title><![CDATA[Housing Shortage and Communal Politics in European Cities around 1900: The Cases of Basel 1889 and Belgrade 1906]]></dc:title>
<prism:publicationDate>2010-02-01</prism:publicationDate>
<prism:section>Articles</prism:section>
<prism:volume>26</prism:volume>
<prism:number>1</prism:number>
<prism:startingPage>61</prism:startingPage>
<prism:endingPage>89</prism:endingPage>
</item>
<item rdf:about="http://sih.sagepub.com/cgi/reprint/26/1/91?rss=1">
<title><![CDATA[Harbans Mukhia, Exploring India's Medieval Centuries. Essays in History, Society, Culture and Technology, Delhi, Aakar Books, 2010]]></title>
<link>http://sih.sagepub.com/cgi/reprint/26/1/91?rss=1</link>
<description><![CDATA[]]></description>
<dc:creator><![CDATA[Vanina, E.]]></dc:creator>
<dc:date>2011-02-14T03:21:36-08:00</dc:date>
<dc:identifier>info:doi/10.1177/025764301002600104</dc:identifier>
<dc:identifier>hwp:resource-id:spsih;26/1/91</dc:identifier>
<dc:title><![CDATA[Harbans Mukhia, Exploring India's Medieval Centuries. Essays in History, Society, Culture and Technology, Delhi, Aakar Books, 2010]]></dc:title>
<prism:publicationDate>2010-02-01</prism:publicationDate>
<prism:section>Articles</prism:section>
<prism:volume>26</prism:volume>
<prism:number>1</prism:number>
<prism:startingPage>91</prism:startingPage>
<prism:endingPage>96</prism:endingPage>
</item>
<item rdf:about="http://sih.sagepub.com/cgi/reprint/26/1/96?rss=1">
<title><![CDATA[Pritish Acharya, National Movement and Politics in Orissa, 1920-29 (Sage Series in Modern Indian History-XI), New Delhi, Sage Publications India Pvt. Ltd., 2008]]></title>
<link>http://sih.sagepub.com/cgi/reprint/26/1/96?rss=1</link>
<description><![CDATA[]]></description>
<dc:creator><![CDATA[Krishan, S.]]></dc:creator>
<dc:date>2011-02-14T03:21:36-08:00</dc:date>
<dc:identifier>info:doi/10.1177/025764301002600105</dc:identifier>
<dc:identifier>hwp:resource-id:spsih;26/1/96</dc:identifier>
<dc:title><![CDATA[Pritish Acharya, National Movement and Politics in Orissa, 1920-29 (Sage Series in Modern Indian History-XI), New Delhi, Sage Publications India Pvt. Ltd., 2008]]></dc:title>
<prism:publicationDate>2010-02-01</prism:publicationDate>
<prism:section>Articles</prism:section>
<prism:volume>26</prism:volume>
<prism:number>1</prism:number>
<prism:startingPage>96</prism:startingPage>
<prism:endingPage>101</prism:endingPage>
</item>
</rdf:RDF>